

ABOUT ME

Personal Statement

I am a Clinical Programmer and External Data manager with more than eight years of experience. I currently work as a for large contract research organisation, so I have plenty of experience working well with others as part of a team or agency. I am an enthusiastic and dedicated professional with extensive experience across all areas of database management, programming design and development. A proactive individual with a logical approach to challenges, I perform effectively even within a highly pressurised working environment. I am quick to grasp new ideas and concepts, and to develop innovative and creative solutions to problems.

EXPERIENCE

Syneos Health

June 2019 - Clinical Programmer » Lewes, UK

> Clinical Programmer building and maintining listings and reports for world-wide major sponsors to deliver clinical trial information on the effectiveness of the trial drugs and systems.

Syneos Health

Aug 2013 - June 2019 | External Data Manager » Lewes, UK

> External Data Manager working with a major global pharmaceutical company and its vendors. I am responsible for the programming, specification building and delivering external data for large EU-wide clinical trials.

Sciensus UK

May 2012 - Aug 2013 | Health Informatics Developer » Brighton, UK

> Information design, visual design and implementation of web reporting solutions for a wide range of commercial and health authority clients. Regular duties included: visual design and HTML, CSS & JavaScript , SQL and C# (MVC)

Novartis Pharmaceuticals » Horsham, UK

June 2006 - May 2012 | Safety System Expert

Responsible for the maintenance of the safety database configuration and change control processes and for the technical support to the business users of safety data tools. Providing analysis and queries using SQL and SAS for management decisions leading to Quality Assurance reporting and Corrective Action Planning

Covance Cardiac Services » Crawley, UK

October 2004 - June 2006 | Clinical Data Manager

Accountable for study data accuracy and timeliness and responsible for the global contact and escalation point between Covance Cardiac Safety Services (CCSS) and their sponsors for all data related activities, Managing a team of Data Management & Statistics staff within their Clinical Trial Operation team, Maintenance and creation of SAS programs, Visual Basic Scripts, Transact SQL scripts, system testing processes, and all associated documentation.

CP Ships (UK) Ltd » Crawley, UK

May 1999 - October 2004 | Systems Developer

> Developed the Companies' new Data Warehouse / OLAP / MIS application holding information relating to revenue, clients and transportation of containers worldwide.Provided Microsoft OLAP services for SQL Server 7.0 to produce extended data sets for European offices. This information presented to user using web based Pivot Table lists and Excel 2000. Additional reporting provided using OLAP MDX SQL, local cubes and Access 2000. Responsible for the maintenance of an EDI system using Mercator and Trading Partner products plus its VB and SQL server applications to process vessel statistics at each port call and supplying senior management with performance and volume information for globally placed container vessels.

Brighton Sussex University Hospitals NHS Trust » Brighton, UK

Aug 1992 – May 1999 | Clinical/Emergency Care Effectiveness Coordinator

> Writing and maintaining clinical effectiveness programs for clinicans and hsopital staff to improve care to patiants using evidence-based guidelines

BT Plc » Brighton/London, UK

Sep 1980 – Aug 1992 | Commercial Analyst

> Various Commercial and System Auditor Roles

EDUCATION

University of Westminster » London, UK

1999 – 2001 | Master's Degree in Evaluation of Clinical Practice

University of Brighton » Brighton, UK

1990-1992 | HNC Computer Science

OTHER Info

Dissertation ₹

A Comparative Audit of Renal Dialysis in a District General Hospital

SKILLS

SAS

VB MS SQL Server

MVC3+, Razor 2+, Entity Framework 4.1,

LINQ to Entities, DevExpress, SQL Server

Other

HTML 4, 5	CSS	XHTML 1.1 JavaScript	jQuery	SQL (MySQL, SQL Server)

CONTACT

jeff.anthony.haynes@gmail.com ↗ 32 Gleton Avenue, Hove East Sussex BN3 8LL (+44) 777 303 9627